<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apps on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/tags/apps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apps on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 14:00:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/www.andreacirillo.com/tags/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 50 practical recipes for data analysis with R in one book</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2016/05/11/over-50-practical-recipes-for-data-analysis-with-r-in-one-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2016/05/11/over-50-practical-recipes-for-data-analysis-with-r-in-one-book/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing a blog post! This is a pleasure I was forgetting, and you can guess it looking at last post date of publication: it was around january... you may be wondering: what have you done along this long time? Well, quite a lot indeed:
 changed my job ( I am now working @ Intesa Sanpaolo Banking Group on Basel III statistical models)
 became dad for the third time (and if you are guessing, it’s a boy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to list loaded packages in R: ramazon gets cleaver</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/09/10/how-to-list-loaded-packages-in-r-ramazon-gets-cleaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 09:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/09/10/how-to-list-loaded-packages-in-r-ramazon-gets-cleaver/</guid>
      <description>It was around midnight here in Italy: I shared the code on Github, published a post on G+, Linkedin and Twitter and then went to bed.
In the next hours things got growing by themselves, with pleasant results like the following:
https://twitter.com/DoodlingData/status/635057258888605696
The R community found ramazon a really helpful package.
And I actually think it is: Amazon AWS is nowadays one of the most common tools for online web applications and websites hosting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Afraus: an Unsupervised Fraud Detection Algorithm</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/07/02/introducing-afraus-an-unsupervised-fraud-detection-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 21:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/07/02/introducing-afraus-an-unsupervised-fraud-detection-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>The last Report to the Nation published by ACFE, stated that on average, fraud accounts for nearly the 5% of companies revenues.
   on average, fraud accounts for nearly the 5% of companies revenues   [![Tweet: on average, fraud accounts for nearly the 5% of companies revenues. http://ctt.ec/u5E6x+](http://clicktotweet.com/img/tweet-graphic-4.png)](http://ctt.ec/q3j4X) 
Projecting this number for the whole world GDP, it results that the &amp;ldquo;fraud-country&amp;rdquo; produces something like a GDP 3 times greater than the Canadian GDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a live chat to your Shiny app</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/05/11/how-to-add-live-chat-to-your-shiny-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 21:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/05/11/how-to-add-live-chat-to-your-shiny-app/</guid>
      <description>As I am currently working on a Fraud Analytics Web Application based on Shiny (currently on beta version, more later on this blog) I found myself asking: wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great to add live chat support to my Web Application visitors?
It would indeed!
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_490&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo;] an ancient example of chatting - Camera degli Sposi, Andrea Mantegna 1465 -1474[/caption]
But how to do it?
Unfortunately, looking on Google didn&amp;rsquo;t give any useful result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Querying Google With R</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/11/19/querying-google-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 04:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/11/19/querying-google-with-r/</guid>
      <description>If you have a blog you may want to discover how your website is performing for given keywords on Google Search Engine. As we all know, this topic is not a trivial one.
Problem is that the analogycal solution would be quite time-consuming, requiring you to search your website for every single keyword, on many many pages.
Feeling this way?
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_273&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;] &amp;ldquo;Pain and fear, pain and fear for me&amp;rdquo; - Oliver Twist[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>