<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aws on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 09:19:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>how to list loaded packages in R: ramazon gets cleaver</title>
      <link>/2015/09/10/how-to-list-loaded-packages-in-r-ramazon-gets-cleaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 09:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/10/how-to-list-loaded-packages-in-r-ramazon-gets-cleaver/</guid>
      <description>It was around midnight here in Italy: I shared the code on Github, published a post on G+, Linkedin and Twitter and then went to bed.
In the next hours things got growing by themselves, with pleasant results like the following:
https://twitter.com/DoodlingData/status/635057258888605696
The R community found ramazon a really helpful package.
And I actually think it is: Amazon AWS is nowadays one of the most common tools for online web applications and websites hosting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ramazon: Deploy your Shiny App on AWS with a Function</title>
      <link>/2015/08/18/deploy-your-shiny-app-on-aws-with-a-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/18/deploy-your-shiny-app-on-aws-with-a-function/</guid>
      <description>Because Afraus received a good interest, last month I override shinyapps.io free plan limits.
That got me move my Shiny App on an Amazon AWS instance.
Well, it was not so straight forward: even if there is plenty of tutorials around the web, every one seems to miss a part: upgrading R version, removing shiny-server examples&amp;hellip; And even having all info it is still quite a long, error-prone process.
All this pain is removed by ramazon, an R package that I developed to take care of everything is needed to deploy a shiny app on an AWS instance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>