<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrea Cirillo&#39;s website on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Andrea Cirillo&#39;s website on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>introducing vizscorer: a bot advisor to improve your ggplot plots</title>
      <link>/2018/11/12/introducing-vizscorer-a-bot-advisor-to-improve-your-ggplot-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/12/introducing-vizscorer-a-bot-advisor-to-improve-your-ggplot-plots/</guid>
      <description>introducing vizscorer: a bot advisor to improve your ggplot plots How to measure a good plot? Preparing a training dataset of plots  How to train Machine Learning to recognize a good plot? Can Machine learning talk back to humans? Putting all together: vizscorer and the scorer_bot Where to go from here and how to help    introducing vizscorer: a bot advisor to improve your ggplot plots One of the most frustrating issues I face in my professional life is the plentitude of ineffective reports generated within my company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>getting to know the new definition of default</title>
      <link>/2018/07/13/getting-to-know-the-new-definition-of-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/13/getting-to-know-the-new-definition-of-default/</guid>
      <description>The greatest part of my time at working is spent looking at those great piece of statistical machinery that credit risk models are. That is why I was recently required to prepare a short course about the new definition of default, which is goign to be applied from 01/01/2021 on.
It is quite a unexplored topic in the sector and I haven’t found a lot of teaching material online, that is why I tought to share here the brief deck of slide I produced for the occasion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpdateR package: update R version with a function (on MAC OSX)</title>
      <link>/2018/03/10/updater-package-update-r-version-with-a-function-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/10/updater-package-update-r-version-with-a-function-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>Mac version of updateR function: the UpdateR package how to install the updateR package how to update R version using the updateR package behind the scenes: how updateR works verify that user is running a unix machine get last R version from CRAN run command line commands within R feel free to complain with me    I personally really appreciate the InstallR package from Tal galilli, since it lets you install a great number of tools needed for working with R just running a function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Dataviz Principles and Theory from Tufte</title>
      <link>/2018/02/10/summarising-tufte-theory-of-graphics-and-integrity-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/10/summarising-tufte-theory-of-graphics-and-integrity-principles/</guid>
      <description>theory of data graphics maximise data-ink ratio, within reason maximise data density and the size of the data matrix, within reason treat graphics as paragraphs and shape them appropriately  integrity of data graphics always show data in their context try to produce a small lie factor show data variation, not design variation use as many dimensions as the number of dimensions in your data  how to apply Tufte’s principles in R   I have recently completed a great reading: Edward Tufte’s The visual display of quantitative information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are you being so silent?</title>
      <link>/2017/04/12/why-are-you-being-so-silent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/12/why-are-you-being-so-silent/</guid>
      <description>It has being nearly half an year since the last post about workflower was out, why did I stay so silent for that long?
I have three major updates to explain the silence:
 📚 Good guys atPackt publishing asked me to write one more book about R and data mining, I suppose this is because the first one was well received
 📦 I spend my spare time working on updateR so to get it ready to go on CRAN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>streamline your analyses linking R to sas and more: the workfloweR</title>
      <link>/2016/09/21/streamline-your-analysis-linking-r-to-sas-and-more-the-workflower-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2016 12:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/09/21/streamline-your-analysis-linking-r-to-sas-and-more-the-workflower-experiment/</guid>
      <description>we all know R is the first choice for statistical analysis and data visualisation, but what about big data munging? tidyverse (or we&amp;rsquo;d better say hadleyverse 😏) has been doing a lot in this field, nevertheless it is often the case this kind of activities being handled from some other coding language. Moreover, sometimes you get as an input pieces of analyses performed with other kind of languages or, what is worst, piece of databases packed in proprietary format (like .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2 themes examples</title>
      <link>/2016/08/09/ggplot2-themes-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 20:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/08/09/ggplot2-themes-examples/</guid>
      <description>this short post is exactly what it seems: a showcase of all ggplot2 themes available within the ggplot2 package. I was doing such a list for myself ( you know that feeling &amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;how would it look like with this theme? let&amp;rsquo;s try this one&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;) and at the end I thought it could have be useful for my readers. At least this post will save you the time of trying all differents themes just to have a sense of how they look like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euro 2016 analytics: Who&#39;s playing the toughest game?</title>
      <link>/2016/06/21/euro-2016-analytics-whos-playing-the-toughest-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 15:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/21/euro-2016-analytics-whos-playing-the-toughest-game/</guid>
      <description>I am really enjoying Uefa Euro 2016 Footbal Competition, even because our national team has done pretty well so far. That&amp;rsquo;s why after browsing for a while statistics section of official EURO 2016 website I decided to do some analysis on the data they share ( as at the 21th of June).
Just to be clear from the beginning: we are not talking of anything too rigourus, but just about some interesting questions with related answers gathered mainly through data visualisation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a Checklist for your weekly review (GTD methodology)</title>
      <link>/2016/05/17/a-checklist-for-your-weekly-review-gtd-methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/17/a-checklist-for-your-weekly-review-gtd-methodology/</guid>
      <description>I was crafting this checklist for my personal use, and then I found myself thinking: why should&amp;rsquo;nt I share this useful handful of bullets with my readers? So here we are, find below an useful checklist for your weekly review. The checklist is derived directly from the official GTD book by our great friend David Allen. The greatest quality of the checklist is the minimalist approach: just what you really need to read is written within each point, so that you get through your review as quick as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 50 practical recipes for data analysis with R in one book</title>
      <link>/2016/05/11/over-50-practical-recipes-for-data-analysis-with-r-in-one-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/05/11/over-50-practical-recipes-for-data-analysis-with-r-in-one-book/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing a blog post! This is a pleasure I was forgetting, and you can guess it looking at last post date of publication: it was around january... you may be wondering: what have you done along this long time? Well, quite a lot indeed:
 changed my job ( I am now working @ Intesa Sanpaolo Banking Group on Basel III statistical models)
 became dad for the third time (and if you are guessing, it’s a boy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 in review (let me boast myself a bit :))</title>
      <link>/2016/01/01/2015-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 19:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/01/01/2015-in-review/</guid>
      <description>The WordPress.com stats helper monkeys prepared a 2015 annual report for this blog.

Here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt:
The concert hall at the Sydney Opera House holds 2,700 people. This blog was viewed about **8,800** times in 2015. If it were a concert at Sydney Opera House, it would take about 3 sold-out performances for that many people to see it. Click here to see the complete report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rename a Data Frame Within a Function Passing an Argument</title>
      <link>/2015/12/14/rename-a-data-frame-within-a-function-passing-an-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 21:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/12/14/rename-a-data-frame-within-a-function-passing-an-argument/</guid>
      <description>This is not actually a real post but rather a code snippet surrounded by text.
Nevertheless I think it is a quite useful one: have you ever found yourself writing a function where a data frame is created, wanting to name that data frame based on a custom argument passed to the function?
For instance, the output of your function is a really nice data frame name in a really trivial way, like &amp;ldquo;result&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to list loaded packages in R: ramazon gets cleaver</title>
      <link>/2015/09/10/how-to-list-loaded-packages-in-r-ramazon-gets-cleaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 09:19:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/10/how-to-list-loaded-packages-in-r-ramazon-gets-cleaver/</guid>
      <description>It was around midnight here in Italy: I shared the code on Github, published a post on G+, Linkedin and Twitter and then went to bed.
In the next hours things got growing by themselves, with pleasant results like the following:
https://twitter.com/DoodlingData/status/635057258888605696
The R community found ramazon a really helpful package.
And I actually think it is: Amazon AWS is nowadays one of the most common tools for online web applications and websites hosting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ramazon: Deploy your Shiny App on AWS with a Function</title>
      <link>/2015/08/18/deploy-your-shiny-app-on-aws-with-a-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 21:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/18/deploy-your-shiny-app-on-aws-with-a-function/</guid>
      <description>Because Afraus received a good interest, last month I override shinyapps.io free plan limits.
That got me move my Shiny App on an Amazon AWS instance.
Well, it was not so straight forward: even if there is plenty of tutorials around the web, every one seems to miss a part: upgrading R version, removing shiny-server examples&amp;hellip; And even having all info it is still quite a long, error-prone process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Afraus: an Unsupervised Fraud Detection Algorithm</title>
      <link>/2015/07/02/introducing-afraus-an-unsupervised-fraud-detection-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 21:06:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/02/introducing-afraus-an-unsupervised-fraud-detection-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>The last Report to the Nation published by ACFE, stated that on average, fraud accounts for nearly the 5% of companies revenues.
   on average, fraud accounts for nearly the 5% of companies revenues   [![Tweet: on average, fraud accounts for nearly the 5% of companies revenues. http://ctt.ec/u5E6x+](http://clicktotweet.com/img/tweet-graphic-4.png)](http://ctt.ec/q3j4X) 
Projecting this number for the whole world GDP, it results that the &amp;ldquo;fraud-country&amp;rdquo; produces something like a GDP 3 times greater than the Canadian GDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a live chat to your Shiny app</title>
      <link>/2015/05/11/how-to-add-live-chat-to-your-shiny-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 21:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/11/how-to-add-live-chat-to-your-shiny-app/</guid>
      <description>As I am currently working on a Fraud Analytics Web Application based on Shiny (currently on beta version, more later on this blog) I found myself asking: wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great to add live chat support to my Web Application visitors?
It would indeed!
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_490&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo;] an ancient example of chatting - Camera degli Sposi, Andrea Mantegna 1465 -1474[/caption]
But how to do it?
Unfortunately, looking on Google didn&amp;rsquo;t give any useful result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to list file and folders within a folder ( basic file  app)</title>
      <link>/2015/04/01/how-to-list-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 20:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/04/01/how-to-list-file/</guid>
      <description>I know, we are not talking about analytics and no, this is not going to set me as a great data scientist&amp;hellip; By the way: have you ever wondered how to list all files and folders within a root folder just hitting a button?
I have been looking for something like that quite a lot of times, for instance when asked to write down an index of all the working papers pertaining to a specific audit ( yes, **I am an auditor, **sorry about that): really time-consuming and not really value-adding activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Fraud with Benford&#39;s law (and another Shiny App)</title>
      <link>/2015/02/06/benfords_law_with_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/02/06/benfords_law_with_r/</guid>
      <description>In the early &amp;lsquo;900 Frank Benford observed that &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; was more frequent as first digit in his own logarithms manual. More than one hundred years later, we can use this curious finding to look for fraud on populations of data. just give a try to the shiny app What &amp;lsquo;Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law&amp;rsquo; stands for? Around 1938 Frank Benford, a physicist at the General Electrics research laboratories, observed that logarithmic tables were more worn within first pages: was this casual or due to an actual prevalence of numbers near 1 as first digits?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Github with Rstudio : step-by-step tutorial</title>
      <link>/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Pushing to my Github repository directly from the Rstudio project, avoiding that annoying &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; paste&amp;rdquo; job. Since it is one of Best Practices for Scientific Computing, I have been struggling for a while with this problem. Now that I managed to solve the problem, I think you may find useful the detailed tutorial that follows. I am not going to explain you the reason why you should use Github with your Rstudio project, but if you are asking this to yourself, you may find useful a Stack Overflow discussion on the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Visualisation With R</title>
      <link>/2014/12/05/network-visualisation-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 15:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/05/network-visualisation-in-r/</guid>
      <description>The main reason why After all,I am still an Internal Auditor. Therefore I often face one of the typical internal auditors problems: understand links between people and companies, in order to discover the existence of hidden communities that could expose the company to unknown risks.
the solution: linker In order to address this problem I am developing Linker, a lean shiny app that take 1 to 1 links as an input and gives as output a network map:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Querying Google With R</title>
      <link>/2014/11/19/querying-google-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 04:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/19/querying-google-with-r/</guid>
      <description>If you have a blog you may want to discover how your website is performing for given keywords on Google Search Engine. As we all know, this topic is not a trivial one.
Problem is that the analogycal solution would be quite time-consuming, requiring you to search your website for every single keyword, on many many pages.
Feeling this way?
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_273&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;] &amp;ldquo;Pain and fear, pain and fear for me&amp;rdquo; - Oliver Twist[/caption]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices for Scientific Computing</title>
      <link>/2014/11/05/best-pratice-for-scientific-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 04:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/11/05/best-pratice-for-scientific-computing/</guid>
      <description>I reproduce here below principles from the amazing paper Best Practices for Scientific Computing, published on 2012 by a group of US and UK professors. The main purpose of the paper is to &amp;ldquo;teach&amp;rdquo; good programming habits shared from professional developers to people that weren&amp;rsquo;t born developer, and became developers just for professional purposes.
Scientists spend an increasing amount of time building and using software. However, most scientists are never taught how to do this efficiently Best Practices for Scientific Computing    Write programs for people, not computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>download data to excel from web</title>
      <link>/2014/10/28/download-data-to-excel-from-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 13:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/28/download-data-to-excel-from-web/</guid>
      <description> This simple tutorial will show you how to download data into an excel spreadsheet, creating a web query.
Download data into excel select &amp;rdquo;data&amp;rdquo; tab select &amp;rdquo;from web&amp;rdquo;  input the desidered web URL click &amp;rdquo;go&amp;rdquo; button **select **data you want to download click &amp;rdquo;import&amp;rdquo; button Refresh downloaded data select &amp;rdquo;data&amp;rdquo; tab select &amp;ldquo;connections&amp;rdquo; select your connection click &amp;ldquo;refresh&amp;rdquo; button </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>excel right() function in R</title>
      <link>/2014/10/27/excel-right-function-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 05:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/27/excel-right-function-in-r/</guid>
      <description>as part of the** excel functions in R,** I have developed this custom function, reproducing the excel right() function in th R language. Feel free to copy and use it.
[code language=&amp;ldquo;r&amp;rdquo;] right = function (string, char){ substr(string,nchar(string)-(char-1),nchar(string))} [/code]
you can find other function in the Excel functions in R post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>excel left() function in R</title>
      <link>/2014/10/27/excel-left-function-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 05:27:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/27/excel-left-function-in-r/</guid>
      <description>as part of the excel functions in R, I have developed this custom function, emulating the excel left() function in th R language. Feel free to copy and use it.
left = function (string,char){ substr(string,1,char)} you can find other function in theExcel functions in R post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>excel functions in R</title>
      <link>/2014/10/25/excel-functions-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 22:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/25/excel-functions-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I have started my &amp;rdquo;data-journey&amp;rdquo; from Excel, getting excited by formulas like VLookup(), right() and left().
then datasets got bigger, and I discovered that little spreadsheets were not enough, and look for something bigger and stronger, eventually coming to R.
But as you know, ones never forget the first love.
So, for fun and for practice, I have written down some of excel functions in R.
I hope you will enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visual 10/21: Plotly</title>
      <link>/2014/10/25/data-visual-1021-plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 22:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/25/data-visual-1021-plotly/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn dplyr with RStudio and Datacamp</title>
      <link>/2014/10/23/learn-dplyr-with-rstudio-and-datacamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 12:24:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/23/learn-dplyr-with-rstudio-and-datacamp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Twitter with R</title>
      <link>/2014/10/09/mining-twitter-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 12:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/09/mining-twitter-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Great tutorial on text mining with twitter byPaeng Angnakoon
[youtube=http://youtu.be/mJVcANlkxU8]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Answering to Ben ( functions comparison in R)</title>
      <link>/2014/09/13/functions-comparison-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 15:05:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/13/functions-comparison-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Following the post about %in% operator, I received this tweet: https://twitter.com/benwhite21/status/510520550553165824
I gave a look to the code kindly provided by Ben and then I asked myself: I know dplyr is a really nice package, but which snippet is faster?
to answer the question I&amp;rsquo;ve put the two snippets in two functions:
#Ben snippet dplyr_snippet =function(object,column,vector){ filter(object,object[,column] %in% vector) } #AC snippet Rbase_snippet =function(object,column,vector){ object[object[,column] %in% vector,] }
Then, thanks to the great package microbenchmark, I made a comparison between those two functions, testing the time of execution of both, for 100.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Put Equations into Evernote</title>
      <link>/2014/09/11/equations-in-evernote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/11/equations-in-evernote/</guid>
      <description>Problem Solution Tutorial 1. find Grapher among your applications 2. write the equation 3. copy the equation as TIFF 4. paste the equation into Evernote other ways to insert equations into evernote    Problem Some time ago I was looking for an easy way to put some math writing within my Evernote notes trough my Mac device. Even if there is no official solution to the problem and the feature request is still pending within Evernote dedicated forum, I finally came out with a very simple way to solve your problem out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippet: subsetting data frame in R by vector</title>
      <link>/2014/09/02/r-subset-data-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 08:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/02/r-subset-data-frame/</guid>
      <description>Problem: you haveto subset a data frame using as criteria the exact match of a vector content.
for instance:
you have a dataset with some attributes, and you have a vector with some values of one of the attributes. You want to make a filter based on the values in the vector. Example: sales records, each record is a deal.
The vector is a list of selected customers you are interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturation with Parallel Computation in R</title>
      <link>/2014/07/28/parallel_computation_in_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 20:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/07/28/parallel_computation_in_r/</guid>
      <description>I have just saturated all my PC:
full is the 4gb RAM

and so is the CPU (I7 4770 @3.4 GHZ)

Parallel Computation in R which is my secret?
the doParallel package for R on mac
The package lets you make some very useful parallel computation, giving you the possibility to use all the potentiality of your CPU.
As a matter of fact, the standard R option is to use just on of the cores you have got on your PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Visualize Entertainment Expenditures on a Bubble Chart</title>
      <link>/2014/07/12/how-to-visualize-entertainment-expenditures-on-a-bubble-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 07:27:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/07/12/how-to-visualize-entertainment-expenditures-on-a-bubble-chart/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been recently asked to analyze some Board entertainment expenditures in order to acquire sufficient assurance about their nature and responsible.
In response to that request I have developed a little Shiny app with an interesting reactive Bubble chart.
The plot, made using ggplot2 package, is composed by: a categorical x value, represented by the clusters identified in the expenditures population A numerical y value, representing the total amount expended Points defined by the total amount of expenditure in the given cluster for each company subject.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work - rules for focused success in adistracted world</title>
      <link>/bookstack/deep_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/deep_work/</guid>
      <description>a really brief summary what I have succesfully applied from this book has it worked?   a really brief summary There are two diverging trends in our society:
 by one hand in our society tend to succeed those whose can be considered high-skilled like real professionals in data science realm on the other hand the same society force ourself to an increasingly fragmented style of life, full of shallow stimolous and activites, like reading Facebook notifications or immediately reply to emails  That is why the good author of the book calls for a regaining of the ability to perform Deep Work i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R data mining</title>
      <link>/pubblications/featured_book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubblications/featured_book/</guid>
      <description>R data mining is a data mining crime book, a new kind of book we developed with good guys at Packt and the great statistician Enrico Pegoraro.

What is a data mining crime book? It is a book stucture to teach you data mining fundamentals while immersing you in a crime case.
Within R data mining you will be immersed into the life of a wholesale company, where suddenly a misterious drop in profits arises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rstudio for R Statistical computing Cookbook</title>
      <link>/pubblications/rstudio_cookbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubblications/rstudio_cookbook/</guid>
      <description>Rstudio for R Statistical computing Cookbook is an useful contribution to the R community, and especially for those just starting off with R.

The book is a concentrated of recipes targeted to the average R user to get him from being in the mean to the become an outlier. Aside from statistical analogies, this book provides recipes to perform relevant activities within all phases of data analysis projects, and literally:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So Good They Can&#39;t Ignore You</title>
      <link>/bookstack/so_good_ignore_you/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/so_good_ignore_you/</guid>
      <description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aenean commodo ligula eget dolor. Aenean massa. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec quam felis, ultricies nec, pellentesque eu, pretium quis, sem. Nulla consequat massa quis enim. Donec pede justo, fringilla vel, aliquet nec, vulputate eget, arcu. In enim justo, rhoncus ut, imperdiet a, venenatis vitae, justo. Nullam dictum felis eu pede mollis pretium. Integer tincidunt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Visual Display of Quantitative Information</title>
      <link>/bookstack/visual_display_of_quantitative_information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/visual_display_of_quantitative_information/</guid>
      <description>theory of data graphics maximise data-ink ratio, within reason maximise data density and the size of the data matrix, within reason treat graphics as paragraphs and shape them appropriately  integrity of data graphics always show data in their context try to produce a small lie factor show data variation, not design variation use as many dimensions as the number of dimensions in your data    I have recently completed a great reading: the famous Edward Tufte’s The visual display of quantitative information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>brief bio I am Andrea Cirillo, a Quantitative Analyst currently employed in a bank. My kind of mixed background ( HR guys tended to call it a resilient path, when we talked about it) is composed of a first relevant dose of artistic studies in the Brera High School, followed from an heavy dose of economics and mathematics at the Catholic University of Jesus Sacred Heart, finally crowned from Auditing, Statistics and Data Science Courses by Auditing, Hacking and Banking firms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contacts</title>
      <link>/contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contacts/</guid>
      <description>I do not have a general purposes email ( I actually use to have one but it got irredeemably full of spam) but I carefully crafted three main channels to get exposed to all relevant and promising opportunities.
You can find them below:
Proposals of Blog Post/Speaches author at andreacirillo.com
 Collaboration proposals you can use my linkedin profile to get in touch with me for proposals of every kind of collaboration, either requesting to connect or sending inmail messages: linkedin profile</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paletter speech</title>
      <link>/pubblications/paletter_speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pubblications/paletter_speech/</guid>
      <description>On november 20th I was requested to make a keynote speech at the 9th MilanoR meeting, the most relevant italian meeting of R users.
The main topic of the speech was one of my last coding fatigues: the Paletter package, a new R package able to derive an optimised colour palette from any kind of image.
 You can also find a kind reportage of the evening directly on the official MilanoR blog, and the full deck of slides online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the Pragmatic Programmer</title>
      <link>/bookstack/pragmatic_programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/pragmatic_programmer/</guid>
      <description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetuer adipiscing elit. Aenean commodo ligula eget dolor. Aenean massa. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec quam felis, ultricies nec, pellentesque eu, pretium quis, sem. Nulla consequat massa quis enim. Donec pede justo, fringilla vel, aliquet nec, vulputate eget, arcu. In enim justo, rhoncus ut, imperdiet a, venenatis vitae, justo. Nullam dictum felis eu pede mollis pretium. Integer tincidunt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the Seven Habits of Highly Effective People</title>
      <link>/bookstack/seven_habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/seven_habits/</guid>
      <description>a really brief summary Be proactive Begin with the end in mind Put thirst things first think win-win Seek First to Understand, Then to be Understood Synergize sharpen the saw  has it worked?   a really brief summary All of the book listed within the bookstack were relevant book for me, but this one was actually crucial for my personal and professional development.
I started reading it after being excluded from a talent program, while I was questioning my ability to construct effective relationship with others and being relevant part of a team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>