<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paletter on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/tags/paletter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paletter on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/paletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the paletteR Gallery </title>
      <link>/2019/11/26/introducing-the-paletter-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/26/introducing-the-paletter-gallery/</guid>
      <description>celebrating beauty add your own masterpiece discover more about paletteR   celebrating beauty PaletteR, the package that allows you to create an optimized palette from an image, has been staying around for nearly two years, and #rstats users have made a lot of great stuff with it. I had therefore took the time to collect what I have found around the web, just to celebrate this beauty. You can find them below in a slideshow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to use PaletteR to automagically build palettes from pictures</title>
      <link>/2018/05/08/how-to-use-paletter-to-automagically-build-palettes-from-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/08/how-to-use-paletter-to-automagically-build-palettes-from-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Introducing paletter Installing paletter Creating a palette from your image  Functional specification Reading a picture into the RGB colourspace Processing the RGB image trough kmeans Moving to the hsv colours space Removing outliers Optimising palette  How to apply paletteR in ggplot2 Join us   I live in Italy, and more precisely in Milan, a city known for fashion and design events. During a lunch break I was visiting the Pinacoteca di Brera, a 200 centuries old museum.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>