<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/categories/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the paletteR Gallery </title>
      <link>/2019/11/26/introducing-the-paletter-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/11/26/introducing-the-paletter-gallery/</guid>
      <description>celebrating beauty add your own masterpiece   celebrating beauty PaletteR, the package that allows you to create an optimized palette from an image, has been staying around for nearly two years, and #rstats users have made a lot of great stuff with it. I had therefore took the time to collect what I have found around the web, just to celebrate this beauty. You can find them below in a slideshow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a quick ride on pagedown: create PDFs from Rmarkdown </title>
      <link>/2019/01/27/a-quick-ride-on-pagedown-create-pdf-from-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/27/a-quick-ride-on-pagedown-create-pdf-from-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Do we really need a package like pagedown? installing pagedown selecting the preferred template filling in and rendering the template finally obtaining the desired PDF file my suggestions for improvements   I recently came across the good talk by the always good Yiuhi Xie at the Rstudio conference about Pagedown. You can see it by yourself reaching out the rstudio website or clicking the image below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>introducing vizscorer: a bot advisor to improve your ggplot plots</title>
      <link>/2018/11/12/introducing-vizscorer-a-bot-advisor-to-improve-your-ggplot-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/11/12/introducing-vizscorer-a-bot-advisor-to-improve-your-ggplot-plots/</guid>
      <description>introducing vizscorer: a bot advisor to improve your ggplot plots How to measure a good plot? Preparing a training dataset of plots  How to train Machine Learning to recognize a good plot? Can Machine learning talk back to humans? Putting all together: vizscorer and the scorer_bot Where to go from here and how to help    introducing vizscorer: a bot advisor to improve your ggplot plots One of the most frustrating issues I face in my professional life is the plentitude of ineffective reports generated within my company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to use PaletteR to automagically build palettes from pictures</title>
      <link>/2018/05/08/how-to-use-paletter-to-automagically-build-palettes-from-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/08/how-to-use-paletter-to-automagically-build-palettes-from-pictures/</guid>
      <description>Introducing paletter Installing paletter Creating a palette from your image  Functional specification Reading a picture into the RGB colourspace Processing the RGB image trough kmeans Moving to the hsv colours space Removing outliers Optimising palette  How to apply paletteR in ggplot2 Join us   I live in Italy, and more precisely in Milan, a city known for fashion and design events. During a lunch break I was visiting the Pinacoteca di Brera, a 200 centuries old museum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpdateR package: update R version with a function (on MAC OSX)</title>
      <link>/2018/03/10/updater-package-update-r-version-with-a-function-on-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/10/updater-package-update-r-version-with-a-function-on-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>Mac version of updateR function: the UpdateR package how to install the updateR package how to update R version using the updateR package behind the scenes: how updateR works verify that user is running a unix machine get last R version from CRAN run command line commands within R accomplisments and further developments feel free to complain with me    I personally really appreciate the InstallR package from Tal galilli, since it lets you install a great number of tools needed for working with R just running a function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Dataviz Principles and Theory from Tufte</title>
      <link>/2018/02/10/summarising-tufte-theory-of-graphics-and-integrity-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/10/summarising-tufte-theory-of-graphics-and-integrity-principles/</guid>
      <description>theory of data graphics maximise data-ink ratio, within reason maximise data density and the size of the data matrix, within reason treat graphics as paragraphs and shape them appropriately  integrity of data graphics always show data in their context try to produce a small lie factor show data variation, not design variation use as many dimensions as the number of dimensions in your data  how to apply Tufte’s principles in R   I have recently completed a great reading: Edward Tufte’s The visual display of quantitative information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Github with Rstudio : step-by-step tutorial</title>
      <link>/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Pushing to my Github repository directly from the Rstudio project, avoiding that annoying &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; paste&amp;rdquo; job. Since it is one of Best Practices for Scientific Computing, I have been struggling for a while with this problem. Now that I managed to solve the problem, I think you may find useful the detailed tutorial that follows. I am not going to explain you the reason why you should use Github with your Rstudio project, but if you are asking this to yourself, you may find useful a Stack Overflow discussion on the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>