<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/categories/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>summarising Tufte: theory of graphics and integrity principles</title>
      <link>/2018/02/10/summarising-tufte-theory-of-graphics-and-integrity-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/10/summarising-tufte-theory-of-graphics-and-integrity-principles/</guid>
      <description>theory of data graphics maximise data-ink ratio, within reason maximise data density and the size of the data matrix, within reason treat graphics as paragraphs and shape them appropriately  integrity of data graphics always show data in their context try to produce a small lie factor show data variation, not design variation use as many dimensions as the number of dimensions in your data conclusions    I have recently completed a great reading: Edward Tufte’s The visual display of quantitative information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Github with Rstudio : step-by-step tutorial</title>
      <link>/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Pushing to my Github repository directly from the Rstudio project, avoiding that annoying &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; paste&amp;rdquo; job. Since it is one of Best Practices for Scientific Computing, I have been struggling for a while with this problem. Now that I managed to solve the problem, I think you may find useful the detailed tutorial that follows. I am not going to explain you the reason why you should use Github with your Rstudio project, but if you are asking this to yourself, you may find useful a Stack Overflow discussion on the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>