<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/tags/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 14:00:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/www.andreacirillo.com/tags/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Over 50 practical recipes for data analysis with R in one book</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2016/05/11/over-50-practical-recipes-for-data-analysis-with-r-in-one-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 14:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2016/05/11/over-50-practical-recipes-for-data-analysis-with-r-in-one-book/</guid>
      <description>Ah, writing a blog post! This is a pleasure I was forgetting, and you can guess it looking at last post date of publication: it was around january... you may be wondering: what have you done along this long time? Well, quite a lot indeed:
 changed my job ( I am now working @ Intesa Sanpaolo Banking Group on Basel III statistical models)
 became dad for the third time (and if you are guessing, it’s a boy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to add a live chat to your Shiny app</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/05/11/how-to-add-live-chat-to-your-shiny-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 21:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/05/11/how-to-add-live-chat-to-your-shiny-app/</guid>
      <description>As I am currently working on a Fraud Analytics Web Application based on Shiny (currently on beta version, more later on this blog) I found myself asking: wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great to add live chat support to my Web Application visitors?
It would indeed!
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_490&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;200&amp;rdquo;] an ancient example of chatting - Camera degli Sposi, Andrea Mantegna 1465 -1474[/caption]
But how to do it?
Unfortunately, looking on Google didn&amp;rsquo;t give any useful result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to list file and folders within a folder ( basic file  app)</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/04/01/how-to-list-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 20:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2015/04/01/how-to-list-file/</guid>
      <description>I know, we are not talking about analytics and no, this is not going to set me as a great data scientist&amp;hellip; By the way: have you ever wondered how to list all files and folders within a root folder just hitting a button?
I have been looking for something like that quite a lot of times, for instance when asked to write down an index of all the working papers pertaining to a specific audit ( yes, **I am an auditor, **sorry about that): really time-consuming and not really value-adding activity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Github with Rstudio : step-by-step tutorial</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/12/28/using-github-with-rstudio-step-by-step-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Pushing to my Github repository directly from the Rstudio project, avoiding that annoying &amp;ldquo;copy &amp;amp; paste&amp;rdquo; job. Since it is one of Best Practices for Scientific Computing, I have been struggling for a while with this problem. Now that I managed to solve the problem, I think you may find useful the detailed tutorial that follows. I am not going to explain you the reason why you should use Github with your Rstudio project, but if you are asking this to yourself, you may find useful a Stack Overflow discussion on the topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>download data to excel from web</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/10/28/download-data-to-excel-from-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 13:02:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/10/28/download-data-to-excel-from-web/</guid>
      <description> This simple tutorial will show you how to download data into an excel spreadsheet, creating a web query.
Download data into excel select &amp;rdquo;data&amp;rdquo; tab select &amp;rdquo;from web&amp;rdquo;  input the desidered web URL click &amp;rdquo;go&amp;rdquo; button **select **data you want to download click &amp;rdquo;import&amp;rdquo; button Refresh downloaded data select &amp;rdquo;data&amp;rdquo; tab select &amp;ldquo;connections&amp;rdquo; select your connection click &amp;ldquo;refresh&amp;rdquo; button </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Twitter with R</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/10/09/mining-twitter-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 12:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/10/09/mining-twitter-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Great tutorial on text mining with twitter byPaeng Angnakoon
[youtube=http://youtu.be/mJVcANlkxU8]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Put Equations into Evernote</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/09/11/equations-in-evernote/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 16:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/09/11/equations-in-evernote/</guid>
      <description>Problem
If you have to put some math writing into your Evernote notes, and you have a Mac device, there is a very simple way to solve your problem out.
Solution
This way is called Grapher, a built-in application for visualising math stuffs.
Tutorial
Here below a simple tutorial:
1. find Grapher among your applications. You can either search for it within Spotlight or using the launchpad.

2. write the equation you would like to put into your Evernote note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code snippet: subsetting data frame in R by vector</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/09/02/r-subset-data-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 08:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/09/02/r-subset-data-frame/</guid>
      <description>Problem: you haveto subset a data frame using as criteria the exact match of a vector content.
for instance:
you have a dataset with some attributes, and you have a vector with some values of one of the attributes. You want to make a filter based on the values in the vector. Example: sales records, each record is a deal.
The vector is a list of selected customers you are interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturation with Parallel Computation in R</title>
      <link>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/07/28/parallel_computation_in_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 20:14:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/www.andreacirillo.com/2014/07/28/parallel_computation_in_r/</guid>
      <description>I have just saturated all my PC:
full is the 4gb RAM

and so is the CPU (I7 4770 @3.4 GHZ)

Parallel Computation in R which is my secret?
the doParallel package for R on mac
The package lets you make some very useful parallel computation, giving you the possibility to use all the potentiality of your CPU.
As a matter of fact, the standard R option is to use just on of the cores you have got on your PC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>