<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bookstack on Andrea Cirillo</title>
    <link>/bookstack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bookstack on Andrea Cirillo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/bookstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Work - rules for focused success in adistracted world</title>
      <link>/bookstack/deep_work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/deep_work/</guid>
      <description>a really brief summary what I have succesfully applied from this book has it worked?   a really brief summary There are two diverging trends in our society:
 by one hand in our society tend to succeed those whose can be considered high-skilled like real professionals in data science realm on the other hand the same society force ourself to an increasingly fragmented style of life, full of shallow stimolous and activites, like reading Facebook notifications or immediately reply to emails  That is why the good author of the book calls for a regaining of the ability to perform Deep Work i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Visual Display of Quantitative Information</title>
      <link>/bookstack/visual_display_of_quantitative_information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/visual_display_of_quantitative_information/</guid>
      <description>theory of data graphics maximise data-ink ratio, within reason maximise data density and the size of the data matrix, within reason treat graphics as paragraphs and shape them appropriately  integrity of data graphics always show data in their context try to produce a small lie factor show data variation, not design variation use as many dimensions as the number of dimensions in your data    I have recently completed a great reading: Edward Tufte’s The visual display of quantitative information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the Seven Habits of Highly Effective People</title>
      <link>/bookstack/seven_habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bookstack/seven_habits/</guid>
      <description>a really brief summary Be proactive Begin with the end in mind Put thirst things first think win-win Seek First to Understand, Then to be Understood Synergize sharpen the saw  has it worked?   a really brief summary All of the book listed within the bookstack were relevant book for me, but this one was actually crucial for my personal and professional development.
I started reading it after being excluded from a talent program, while I was questioning my ability to construct effective relationship with others and being relevant part of a team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>